Boy, this is the life.
It is lovely, isn't it?
I hate the thought
of driving back to the city.
It is too bad it can't last.
Why can't it?
Why can't things be like this always?
We do get along well, Cathy, don't we?
Yes, George.
Well, I guess people would think us silly.
What do you mean, George?
I'm only a junior architect.
Well, what's wrong with that?
Just that a junior doesn't
make the big money.
You make more than enough
to support a family.
Then you've thought about it, too!
Of course, silly.
Do you think I'd keep
seeing you if I hadn't?
Think you could be happy with me?
I know I will.
Well, that was easier
than I thought it would be.
It isn't the way I imagined
I'd be proposed to either.
Just so we'll have a good story
to tell our grandchildren...
Hmm, is this the menu?
Doesn't look like there's much
to eat this morning.
Oh, is that so?
Well, you just close your eyes.
Close my eyes? What for?
Just close your eyes.
- Now?
- Now.
- Strawberries and cream!
- Mhm!
Honey!
Young lady, what's the occasion
for all this attention?
Oh, I just saw them in the market
yesterday and thought you would like some.
Do you realize this
is my favorite breakfast?
Of course, darling.
Do you realize this is the first time you've
served them to me since our honeymoon?
Yes, darling.
And do you realize
that was nearly a year ago?
Yes, darling.
Well, then why haven't
we had them more often?
But darling,
strawberries don't grow in the snow!
- That's no excuse.
- Oh.
Have you been happy, sweetie?
Very happy.
- No regrets?
- None, darling.
Do you have to work tonight, George?
I really should, why, honey?
You've been working so hard lately.
Can't you take tonight off?
Why, did you have anything in mind?
Darling, don't you remember?
We're supposed to go to Bill
and Janet's baby shower this evening.
Baby shower?
I thought they just had a baby!
What are they, rabbits?
You goof, this is for the Graysons' baby.
Don't you remember anything?
Oh, sure, I'd forgotten.
Well, all right, I enjoy things like that.
Say, why don't we see
those kids more often?
I don't know, George.
It seems like they're always busy
with their families.
They don't have time
to get out with the gang anymore.
Maybe they don't want to.
Why shouldn't they want to?
Honestly, Cathy, do you really enjoy
these parties we've been going to?
Not especially, George,
but we have to have some recreation.
I agree, but they do so
much drinking lately.
I know, most of them drink a lot,
but they're just having a good time.
Cathy, that isn't all.
What do you mean, darling?
Sometimes they go a little too far.
I'm not interested in someone else's wife
and I don't want someone else
making passes at my wife.
Nobody's making passes at me, darling.
I don't mean you, but I've seen plenty.
Take Frank Grover, for instance.
I know he's a friend of mine,
but I can't get used to the way
he tries to take over every girl he sees.
You take things too seriously.
I'm sure he doesn't mean anything wrong.
Well, maybe not, but he takes on
a little too much territory.
You're just jealous.
Just because Frank's single
and can run around
with as many girls as he wants,
you think he's a wolf.
Well, if he's not a wolf,
how can he give such a good imitation?
Oh, George, let's not quarrel about Frank.
He isn't that important.
Okay, sweet.
I still don't like these parties, though.
I know, darling.
I really don't enjoy them much either,
but what else can we do for entertainment?
You work late so often,
and when you do come home early,
you bring your work with you.
Maybe I have been neglecting you, sweet,
but it's just because I want
to make a real home for you.
I like a nice place, too, but I'd like to have
you take enough time off to enjoy it with me.
I guess it is pretty dull for you at that.
I'll try to take enough time
off from my work so we can be together more.
Speaking of work, I'd better get going.
Oh, I forgot to tell you,
Frank Grover is coming over this morning.
He's gonna take me to work;
it's about a divorce case he's handling.
The husband works in my office
and Frank has to pick up some papers.
Well, speak of the devil.
Never mind, honey, I'll get it.
- How are you, Frank?
- I'm at death's door.
I went to a little social gathering last
night and the lemonade just about killed me.
You'd better ease
up on that lemonade, chum.
- It's beginning to get the best of you.
- Oh, I'll be all right.
I'm just a little short on sleep,
that's all.
Who was at the party last night?
Oh, everybody you know, the usual crowd.
How come you and Cathy weren't there?
- Work.
- You and your midnight oil.
What are you trying to do,
knock yourself out?
And tell me, how do you keep
that beautiful wife of yours
entertained while you're working?
Oh, Cathy doesn't mind.
She knows I'm working for our future.
Don't get lost in that future
of yours, chum.
Worry about tomorrow tomorrow,
that's my motto.
All right, Casanova,
wait till I get my coat.
How do you feel this morning, Frank?
Oh, I feel great!
Hey, you look terrific, Cathy!
Thank you!
Are you going to Bill and Janet's
baby party this evening?
Baby party? Stop it, Cathy.
You don't really expect me to sit around
drinking tea all evening!
Besides, I get the jitters around these people
that get themselves all wrapped up in their kids.
Why, Frank,
what's the matter with children?
What are you getting so
defensive about, Cathy?
You and George aren't thinking
about the patter of little feet, are you?
I don't think having children
is such a bad idea.
Oh, are you ready to go?
Oh, say, I almost forgot.
Are you two going to
the country club dance this Friday?
Lord, Frank,
I don't see how we can make it.
Next Friday catches me right in the middle
of my month end reports.
I'm sorry, I know Cathy would like to go.
Well, why not?
If I do, will you get me home early?
Sure, Cathy, anything you say.
Go ahead, Frank, I'll be right out.
Okay. Goodbye, Cathy.
What is this, Cathy,
are you gonna step out on me?
Don't be silly, George.
If you didn't have to work,
we could go together.
You don't mind if I go by myself, do you?
Frank will bring me home early.
Darling,
how can you want to go with Frank?
Frank's bark is worse than his bite.
I don't think he's nearly as bad
as he's supposed to be.
Anyway, I can take care of myself.
Now you'd better get going, darling.
We can talk about it tonight if you want.
Hello?
Oh, hello, George.
No, I just got here.
No, he's still here with me.
- What?
- I said I'd be home in a few moments.
You'd better get that gigolo out before I get
there, or I'll kick him out myself.
Uh-oh.
What's the matter, sugar?
George is pretty sore
about you being here.
Maybe you had better leave, Frank.
The indignant husband, eh?
Catherine, you make me feel melodramatic.
Or maybe it's just mellow.
Frank, George is all right.
He doesn't mean... he's just--
Just a husband, is that it, Cathy?
Frank, you know that's not what I mean.
I think you'd better go.
Thanks for everything.
Cathy, you're precious.
Okay, kiss your gigolo goodnight.
Frank, you shouldn't have.
Why did you do that?
Well, did you enjoy yourself?
Mhm. I would've enjoyed myself more
if you had been there, though.
Why? Frank run out of gas
and make you walk?
- Or did he just make you?
- Don't be stupid, George.
Frank is just a friend.
He knows I'm your wife,
he wouldn't try to play around with me.
Oh, no, no, of course not.
He's a perfect little angel.
He wouldn't touch a hair on your head
unless he thought he could get away with it.
Well, I'm not going to argue about it,
I'm too tired.
I think I'll get ready for bed.
I should think that even if
you don't trust Frank, you could trust me.
I know, Cathy, it's just that
I know Frank's tricks and I worry.
I've seen him in action, you know.
Well, darling,
you don't have to worry about me.
I'm perfectly capable
of taking care of myself,
and if the occasion should arise,
I could take care of Frank, too.
I hope so, sweet.
Anyway, darling, I only went with him
to make you jealous.
So that's your alibi.
Okay.
Come around here where I can see you.
Hey, you look sharp in that thing!
Think so? I saved it to wear for you.
You'd better, that thing
would give somebody ideas!
Well, darling, it's your own fault.
It's the one you got me for my birthday.
- It's a good thing I'm your husband.
- The way you talk.
George, what did you think of Bill
and Janet's baby shower the other night?
What's the matter, honey?
Trying to change the subject?
No, darling, but I was just wondering
if you would want to be a father, too,
after seeing how proud and happy Bill was.
Why, sure, darling,
but what brought this on?
Why, I was just wondering
about what you were saying the other day.
I mean, about having
a real family of our own.
I remember, Cathy.
I meant it, too.
Well then, darling,
can't we have our baby now?
I mean, can't we start planning
on having our baby?
I'd like to have him soon.
It's kind of lonely around here
when you're not home.
Anyway, I think you'd look cute
changing his diapers
when you come home at night.
You've already decided
we're going to have a he?
Well, I thought we could have a boy now,
then after a while,
we could give him
a little sister to play with.
We could make a nursery
out of your bedroom easily enough--
Hold on, wait a minute.
Let's get Junior on his way
before we start worrying about his sister.
Besides, what if Junior's a girl?
I never thought about that.
What if he is? We'll just have
to keep on trying till Junior comes along.
Okay, darling, okay.
But really, Cathy, I want a family
as much as you do.
You know, darling, you talk a lot
about wanting a family.
Don't you know that talk
won't get you anywhere?
Woman, what are you hinting?
George, I'm sleepy.
Let's go to bed.
Sleepy, huh?
Go to bed?
Talk won't get me anywhere indeed.
- George.
- Mhm?
You meant what you said last
night, didn't you?
I mean, it wasn't just last night, was it?
Certainly I meant it.
Then we can go ahead and plan on a baby?
I mean, we're going to have Junior?
You're going to have Junior?
You are?
Cathy, do you feel all right?
Do you want me to call a doctor?
How can you tell,
darling, so soon, I mean?
No, no, you goof,
I'm not going to have a baby!
Just yet, anyway.
I only wanted to ask you
when we could have Junior.
Oh, whew, Cathy, don't scare me like that!
I guess we can plan
on having Junior any time.
Oh, that's wonderful.
I'll go ahead and start planning.
You think about it today and we'll
talk about it when I get home tonight.
Say, I'd better get going.
George, will you be home early tonight?
Why?
Well, at the dance last night, I remembered
it was our turn to have a party,
so I invited a few of the kids
over tonight.
Oh, Cathy, you didn't!
After all our talk about these brawls,
you went and planned one anyway.
- What for?
- I don't know, I'm sorry.
I guess I forgot how you felt about them.
Well, I guess you'll
just have to call it off.
Oh, George, I can't do
that, it's too late now.
Can't we have just this one?
I'm sorry, Cathy, you can have
your party if you want,
but I intend to stay at the office tonight
until it's over.
I don't want any part of it.
Oh, George, you can't do that.
You can't leave me alone
with a house full of people.
No, well, I'm going to do just that.
If you want your party so badly,
you go ahead and have it.
If you decide to call it off,
phone me and let me know.
Hello?
Oh, hello, George, where are you?
I'm still working.
Have you decided what
you're going to do about that party?
Oh, it's already started.
George, won't you come on home?
Don't be so stubborn.
Well, all right then,
I'll see you when you get here.
Goodbye.
Come on, Cathy!
Stop looking like the last rose of summer.
Pour yourself another drink
and let's have a good time!
It's your party!
This darn fool is so drunk,
he can hardly stand!
I have a good mind
to let him fall flat on his face!
What do you mean? I'm sober as a judge!
Maybe I should make him a cup of coffee.
- Do you think that would help?
- Oh, don't bother.
I'll have Frank take him for a walk
when he gets here.
By the way, where is that character?
He'll be here pretty soon.
He called and said he was on his way.
Is he bringing anybody with him or are you
supposed to be his girl tonight?
I'm not his girl any night.
He's bringing someone.
I don't know who, though.
He made a crack about
rolling out the red carpet,
'cause he's bringing a celebrity.
That doesn't sound like anybody I know.
Maybe he's trying to break
into the social register.
Maybe.
Say, you got a long
shot at the races today.
Yes, I won $300.
Well, what did you do with all that money?
- Bought new clothes.
- What'd you buy?
Lots of things.
A new skirt, a short one.
How short?
- To here.
- Very interesting.
What else?
A pair of tennis shorts.
Short?
To here.
Tell me more!
Bathing suit.
Well?
To here!
Mm, must be some money left.
Tell me more.
Oh, I've got a complete
outfit for everything.
- Everything?
- Mhm.
Well, for riding, I've got riding clothes.
For tennis, I've got tennis clothes.
For afternoon, I've got afternoon clothes.
For evening, I've got evening clothes.
And for night, night clothes!
Say, remind me to invite you
to my birthday party!
What's all the hilarity about?
Are you two behaving yourselves?
Now, Cathy, you didn't invite us
to your party to behave ourselves!
Well, that must be Frank
and his celebrity now.
If you can blow a fanfare,
now's the time to do it!
- Are we too late for a drink?
- Of course not!
I was beginning to think you had decided
to skip this party, though.
Not while you and a little liquor
are around, my sweet.
Oh, Cathy, I want you to meet
Miss Dolores LaFleur.
- Dolores, Cathy.
- How do you do, Miss LaFleur?
Oh, quite well, my dear.
The famous Broadway actress, you know.
Oh, yes, yes, it was--
The Mansion of Tears with Cartwright,
you know.
Oh, yes, so nice of you to come!
I thought Frank was kidding or joking
when he said he was bringing
a celebrity to our party.
Oh, I understand, my dear.
Frank is so droll.
One never quite knows
when he's being facetious.
Miss LaFleur is thinking about shedding
her latest husband while she's here,
so she came to me.
You see how a good divorce lawyer's
reputation precedes him?
Don't be silly, darling.
The only reason I chose you is because you're
the best looking lawyer in town.
You ability had nothing to do with it.
Well, that's the strangest recommendation
for a lawyer I've ever heard!
Oh, here come Betty and Don!
- Hiya, good looking!
- Hello, angel!
You certainly look like the answer
to my dreams tonight!
You think so?
Thank you, sir, for those very kind words.
You don't look too repulsive yourself!
- Hi, Don.
- Oh, hello!
You must be the celebrity!
Cathy was telling me
Frank was bringing the blue book.
Oh, Miss LaFleur, I'd like you
to meet Mrs. Betty Williams.
- Betty, Dolores.
- Hiya, Dolores!
So where have I seen her before?
The Mansion of Tears?
Well, I ain't never been in jail, honey,
but I've sure seen you someplace.
Do you always allow your guests
to become so inebriated
at your soirees, my dear?
Ineb--ine--inebra--say,
what's the matter with her?
She thinks I'm drunk
and here I am as sober as a judge.
Sure, Don, sure.
Look, why don't you get Cathy
and Dolores a drink, huh?
And you don't mind if I have this dance
with your wife, do you, old man?
No, of course not.
You ladies will excuse me,
I'll bring some refreshments.
Well, it seems my Prince Charming
has deserted me.
I trust he doesn't think he can get away
with it for the rest of the evening.
Well, Don will see that those two
don't spend too much time together.
I doubt if this Don person
will be with us much longer.
He's quite disgustingly drunk, isn't he?
Don can go on like that for hours.
Wait till he tries
his magic tricks on you.
Here he comes now.
For you.
And you.
- How about cutting the rug, gorgeous?
- Cutting a rug?
I'm afraid I don't
understand, Mr. Williams.
He means he'd like to dance, Miss LaFleur.
This is the first time I ever needed
an interpreter to talk to my babe.
My dear Mr. Williams, I am not yours
and I most certainly am not a babe.
If you must be entirely plebeian,
kindly direct your attentions elsewhere.
Okay, babe, no offense.
My dear sir, rather than using
your energies on me,
I would suggest you pay
a little more attention to your wife.
Ah, they look real cozy, don't they?
That Frank is quite a card.
Say, that reminds me.
Have you seen my latest card trick yet?
Here, pick one, babe.
Mr. Williams, please,
I haven't the slightest interest
in your prestidigitation.
My preskibit--prestidi--
Heck, I didn't expect you to be interested
in my prestidigitation.
I just wanted to show you my card trick.
Never mind, Don, why don't you
show Phil your card trick?
Okay, Cathy.
See you later, babe.
Hey, people, got any more
of that hilarity juice?
Sure, Don, I'll make you one.
Don, this is Jerry.
You're real cute!
Here, take one, pick any one of 'em.
Okay, Don. Now what do I do?
Show it to everybody.
What do I do now, Don?
Put her back in the deck.
Okay!
Hold 'em tight.
What do I do now?
Some trick, some trick, some trick!
Hmm, like that.
You're quite a magician, Don.
Here's your drink.
You're quite a girl, beautiful.
How did your audience
like the performance, Mr. Williams?
Oh, fine, fine!
Say, how about you and me cutting the rug?
I told you before,
Mr. Williams, no, thank you.
Oh, that's all right,
you're quite welcome.
Say, baby, why don't we sit
the rest of this one out?
I've got things to tell you
and this isn't the place for it.
That's what I call real interesting.
What were you going to tell me?
Well, you've got beautiful eyes,
you have a beautiful mouth,
you have beautiful shoulders.
Mm, and before you go any further,
let's get a drink.
Okay, come on.
It seems I'm deserted after all.
I doubt if Frank took whatshername
into that other room to teach her legal tricks.
Oh, they'll be back in a minute.
Maybe they just wanted to get away
from the music for a while.
They had better come back
to where the music is.
This is real cozy, real cozy.
Hello, Don, how about a drink?
Thanks.
Let's have a toast.
Here's to it and to it again.
If you don't do it when you get to it,
I hope you never get to it to do it again.
Broad-minded, isn't he?
Hey.
Say what?
Am I interrupting?
Yeah, beat it.
Oh, now that's what I call music!
You know, you remind me of a gal
I saw once in a burlesque show.
I'll bet you could do
as well as she could.
Hmm, think I couldn't?
Why don't you try it? I'll bet the gang
would get a big kick out of it.
Okay, I will.
Come on!
Hold everything, gang! Hold it.
Betty's going to show us how they dance
at the better burlesque houses.
Going ahead, baby, that's your cue!
Say, look at that!
That's all right.
My little honey needs a partner, though.
Hold everything, babe,
I'll be right there.
Please, darling, don't go too far.
Remember, you're a lady.
I guess I'd better put my clothes on.
Take it easy, boy, it's all over.
How was that? Pretty good, yeah?
Pretty good, yeah?
Magnificent, Don.
Hey, that calls for a drink, pal!
Here, drink it down. You need it.
- You're a real pal!
- Sure.
Atta boy!
- Oh, no.
- Hey, Phil, take care of him, will ya?
Frank, that was a mean thing to do.
I didn't think it would him him that hard.
He really must have been lit.
Looks like, uh, Betty forgot something.
I'd better take them into her.
Take it easy, darling.
I'll be right back.
Oh, uh, take care
of Her Highness for me, will ya?
That's more easily said than done, Frank,
she's at a slow boil now.
Well, you can cool her off for me,
can't you?
I'll see you in a couple of minutes.
Where is my hero going now...
as though I couldn't guess?
Oh, he's just taking
Betty's clothes in to her.
He'll be right back.
He'd better--this farce
has gone quite far enough.
Well, that's the end
of Don's tricks for tonight.
I guess I'll have to show you my tricks.
- Don't tell me you do tricks.
- Sure.
Just look.
Say, is that gin?
- Sure.
- Gonna drink it?
You just wait and see.
- Da-dum, da-dum, da-dum--
- Hey, you're terrific.
Oh, Bill, I'm all wet!
What shall I do now?
I guess you'll have to take
off that dress, and let it dry.
I haven't anything under it.
Not anything?
Well, just me.
Wait, there's Don's shirt,
you can put that on.
Thank you, Bill.
How do I look?
Hm, cozy I'd say.
Hello? Hello, George?
Darling, can you come home right away?
What's the matter, Cathy?
Okay, I'm on my way.
Oh, look.
- Look at that.
- Wipe the lipstick off your face, darling.
That shade is a little too vulgar.
What's the matter, dearie,
can't you stand a little competition?
I can compete with any stripper,
amateur or otherwise.
Stripper, huh?
Say, now I remember you.
I thought I'd seen
that bleached mop before.
Dolores LaFleur,
Dolly Flowers of the Star and Garter,
wasn't it?
Sorry, I didn't recognize
you with your clothes on.
- Frank, you've been slumming again.
- Why, you cheap tramp!
Atta boy!
Give her a left hook!
- Darling, let's go.
- Frank, can't you do something to stop it?
Why? This is the best
entertainment I've had in months.
Let 'em fight.
Kill her!
Let's go.
Come on, red.
- Let's go.
- Now girls, no biting.
Now girls, no biting.
Come on, red.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, give it to her.
- Come on.
- Come on, red.
Come on, give it to her, come on.
Let's go.
Oh, my.
Blondie, give it to her, that's it.
- Let's go.
- Let's go, blondie.
What's going on here, anyway?
All right, Grover,
you take over from here.
Get these girls presentable,
then the whole bunch of you
clear out of here, I mean it,
and take Don with you.
Stop it, Cathy.
It's all right, they're leaving now.
Oh, George, it was so terrible.
Everything went wrong.
Well, darling, I don't like to say "I told
you so," but I did tell you, you know that.
Oh, George, please,
let's not quarrel about it.
You realize, Cathy, that we'll never
have another party like this again.
I never want another party like this.
Cathy, what's happening to us?
Why are we breaking up?
We are, you know?
Neither one of us is happy.
I love you, Cathy,
you know that, don't you?
I know you love me.
It isn't that.
I just feel that in some way
our marriage isn't complete,
that we weren't meant
to be married to each other.
Somehow I feel that if we were,
we'd have the children we want,
just as other people do.
Oh, I'm all mixed up.
Do you mean that you want a divorce,
Cathy?
Oh, no, George.
I don't think I want a divorce.
I don't know what to think,
or what I want except a real family,
children of my own.
I guess we were willing to settle for these
parties as long as they were fun,
but they aren't fun anymore.
I guess we need a family.
George, I think I'll go to a doctor
in the next few days.
What for, darling?
Well, we've been married long enough now
so that something should have happened.
Only the other day
I was talking to Mother,
and she asked me when
she was going to be a grandmother.
George, I told her I didn't know.
Oh, and what did she say?
Not very much.
I asked her what she thought
I should do about it,
and she said if I were really worried,
why didn't I go to a doctor?
Yeah?
Did she say any doctor in particular?
Well, she told me
about a Dr. Wright downtown.
She said he's a very good obstetrician
and gyne--
- gyne--
- Gynecologist?
That's it. Anyway I thought that
going to see him wouldn't do any harm.
Do you think we should?
No, I don't think so, but...
he'll probably tell you there's nothing
wrong, but what do we have to lose?
Anyway, it would be better
than going on like this.
Oh, George, I so do want a baby,
and I want to make you happy too.
I know, darling.
We'll phone for an appointment
the first thing Monday morning.
We'll forget this old party ever happened.
Will that make you happy, darling?
Yes, George, I promise.
We have an appointment with Dr. Wright,
Mrs. Bennett and Mr. Bennett.
Doctor's expecting you.
- You may go right in.
- Thank you.
- Good afternoon, Mr. and Mrs. Bennett?
- Yes, doctor, this is Mrs. Bennett.
- How do you do? Please sit down.
- Thank you.
I judged from our telephone conversation
that you and Mr. Bennett are
having difficulty in starting your family.
Well, yes, Doctor.
We thought that possibly
you could tell us what's wrong.
I mean, so many of our friends
are having children while we aren't.
Do you suppose you could find out
what the trouble is?
Possibly. I think the first thing
would to be to give you an examination.
Would you mind waiting
in the other room, please, Mr. Bennett?
Sure.
Will you prepare Mrs. Bennett
for an examination, Miss Mason?
Yes, Doctor.
Now, will remove your things
behind that screen, Mrs. Bennett?
- All of them?
- I think so.
Are you ready, Mrs. Bennett?
- Well, I haven't any clothes on.
- Will you step into this gown, please?
Now, will you just sit on the table,
please?
Gloves, Doctor.
Sit down, Mrs. Bennett.
How does it look to you, doctor?
Mrs. Bennett, I can see no reason at all for you
to worry about your physical condition,
nor about your ability to bear children.
But doctor, if there is nothing
the matter with me,
why aren't my husband and I
having the children we want?
Are we just unlucky?
Luck, as you call it,
may be the reason in your case,
Mrs. Bennett.
But, then again, there might be
other factors involved.
I think while Mr. Bennett is here,
we'd better ask him to come in.
But surely, you aren't suggesting
that there is something wrong with George,
are you, Doctor?
Don't be alarmed, my dear.
I'm only suggesting
that we be sure of our facts
before we attempt to arrive
at a solution of your problem.
All right, Doctor.
- How was it, sweet, was everything all right?
- Uh-huh, he wants to see you, George.
- Why? What for?
- I guess he wants to examine you too.
Well, I guess it's all right.
I'll be back shortly.
Sit down, Mr. Bennett.
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
All right, Doctor.
Mr. Bennett, have you ever had
any form of venereal disease?
No, Doctor,
I never had anything like that.
- Mumps?
- No.
Any serious injury?
No, Doctor.
Why? Do you think it's me?
Mr. Bennett, from my examination
of Mrs. Bennett,
I can find no apparent reason
why she should not become a mother.
We can only surmise that you may be
the reason for your trouble.
But, Doctor, what shall I do?
Take this card to Dr. Farrell,
whose office is in this building.
He's a very competent urologist,
and one who specializes
in that particular phase of your problem.
He will examine you
and send his report to me.
If you can come in tomorrow at, say, 2:00,
I'll have all the facts and shall be
able to give you your answer.
- You'd better bring Mrs. Bennett with you.
- Certainly, Doctor.
I'll see you tomorrow, then.
Miss Mason, will you make an appointment
for Mr. and Mrs. Bennett
at 2:00 tomorrow, please?
Yes, Doctor.
- Dr. Wright will see you now, Mr. Bennett.
- Thank you.
See you later, honey.
Have you found out anything yet, Doctor?
Yes.
I have, Mr. Bennett.
I guess that means that it's me,
that I'm sterile?
I'm afraid that's the word
I was going to have to use, Mr. Bennett,
from the looks of this report.
And being sterile means
that I can never become a father?
- I'm afraid that in your--
- Isn't there some way I can get around this?
No, there isn't.
In some cases,
operations or medication
or other treatment may be beneficial.
In others,
this sort of thing is without help.
Unfortunately, according
to the report of your urologist,
you fall into this latter classification.
I don't understand it, Doctor.
I always thought I was perfectly normal.
At least I seemed to be normal.
Yes, I understand.
It is quite common for a male to have
a normal sex reaction in every way
and still be sterile.
I might explain that through
each drop of male reproductive fluid,
known as semen,
there are as many as 15
million tiny sperms,
each in itself capable
of inducing pregnancy.
Enough of them could be housed in a thimble
to father the entire world ten times over.
In some cases of temporary sterility,
the sperm count may drop as low as 20,000
or 30,000 sperms to the drop of semen.
In these cases,
treatment may be effective.
Isn't there treatment I can take?
No, Mr. Bennett.
According to this report,
your sperms are all completely inactive.
Or, to put it bluntly,
dead.
Oh, I see.
Well, I guess that's that.
You know, Dr. Wright, that throws
a lot of our plans out the window.
I'm sorry, Mr. Bennett.
Would you like to bring Mrs. Bennett in?
Doctor, I hope you won't
think I'm a coward,
but I'd sure appreciate it
if you'd help me tell her.
Certainly, I can quite
appreciate your feelings.
You may call her in.
Well, it's about time.
I thought you had deserted me.
George, what's the matter?
Dr. Wright would like to see
both of us, darling.
All right, but what's wrong?
Sit down, please, both of you.
George, what's the matter?
Cathy, would you mind
if we didn't have Junior?
You mean we can't have
children right away?
Oh, George!
I mean, we can't have
children at all, dear.
Why not?
What Mr. Bennett is trying to say is
that he is incapable of fatherhood.
No, Doctor, you can't be serious.
I'm afraid I am, Mrs. Bennett.
I guess we'll just have
to adopt our family, Cathy.
I won't. I don't want a ready-made family.
If I'm going to have children,
I want them to be mine, my own.
But darling, what else can we do?
Dr. Wright says I'm sterile,
he must know what he's talking about.
I suppose so.
I don't know what to say, Cathy,
except that I'm sorry.
If you two have decided against adoption,
there may be something I can do.
That is, if you want your own child.
- Why, doctor, you don't think--
- No, no, Mrs. Bennett, you misunderstand me.
Here, let me read you this letter
by way of explanation.
"Dear Dr. Wright,
I'm writing you this letter
on my daughter's first birthday.
My husband and I are so happy,
and cannot express to you the gratitude
we feel for telling us
about artificial insemination,
and helping us to have our baby.
Nothing in our lives has
given us such happiness.
And when I look at baby Dorothy,
I bless God that we were sent to you.
My husband joins me in wishing you
the greatest of success in your fine work."
Well, what do you think?
Does that appeal to you?
I don't understand even yet.
What is this artificial
insemination thing?
Have you ever heard of it before, George?
Seems to me I've heard
it mentioned before.
It sounds as though it might be connected
with what you were telling me
a few minutes ago, Dr. Wright.
Well, yes, in a way it is.
It consists, in effect, in removing semen
from a normal, healthy man,
and implanting it in a receptive woman.
Pregnancy takes place,
as in normal conception,
and a normal birth is the result.
To all intents and purposes,
this method is the same
as a normal conception,
except of course the mother
never sees the donor.
How can that be, doctor?
- I thought that the--
- No, no, Mrs. Bennett.
Contact between the father and the mother
is not necessary,
nor in this case desirable.
The male fluid is withdrawn from the donor
and stored under refrigeration
until it is needed.
At that time, it is introduced
into the prospective mother by artificial means.
That is by syringe
or by means of a capsule.
Oh, I see.
Well, what about the selection
of the father?
How can you tell if--
is "donor" the word you use--
is satisfactory?
We do that by examining his background.
We look for the same qualities
and characteristics in him
and in his family background
that we would want to appear in the child.
If his family history reveals
certain admirable traits,
either physical or mental,
we can be sure that these same traits
will appear in him, and in his children.
You see, each male sperm cell
and each female egg
consists of 24 sections
called chromosomes.
Now each of these chromosomes
is the determining factor
in some part or phase of the infant.
One chromosome might
cause the baby to have black hair.
Another might determine
whether his eyes would be blue or brown.
And still another would be the determining
factor in regard to his size.
But Dr. Wright, has there been much work
done in this artificial insemination field?
I mean, is is just a theoretical thing,
or has it been done before?
A tremendous amount of work has been done
in artificial insemination, Mrs. Bennett.
I'll admit
that up till the past few years,
a great majority of it has
been done with livestock.
But the results with all sorts of animals,
and lately with human beings,
have been exceedingly gratifying.
Uh, one more thing, Dr. Wright,
is there any danger in this?
The only possible source of danger
in artificial insemination, Mr. Bennett,
is the same danger that is present
in ordinary childbirth.
In the hands of a competent gynecologist,
however, the patient is perfectly safe.
Well, Dr. Wright, I think my wife and I
had better have a talk about this
before we decide anything.
Thank you for your help, Dr. Wright,
- we'll let you know what we decide.
- All right.
Give what I told you careful
consideration, though, goodbye.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- Goodbye, Dr. Wright.
Miss Mason, will you bring in the files
on our insemination donors, please?
Dr. Wright certainly gave us something
to think about, didn't he?
What do you think we ought to do, Cathy?
I don't know, darling.
I want a baby terribly, but...
having someone else as its father
doesn't seem right.
I'd rather you have a baby that way
than have you as unhappy as you've been
and take the risk of losing you.
Besides, it would be your baby,
which is more than we could say
for an adopted child.
I think if it's all right with you,
I'll ask Mother what she thinks of it.
Certainly.
I think that's good.
Your mother's an intelligent woman,
and having her tell us what she thinks
might help us decide.
All right, darling,
I'll ask her to come over tomorrow.
Now I'd better get us some dinner.
And the doctor assured us that this artificial
insemination wouldn't be dangerous.
Tell me, Mother,
what do you think we should do?
I want a baby of my own,
but I'm not sure that I wouldn't
feel guilty every time I look at it.
Why should you feel guilty, Cathy?
Naturally, it wouldn't be George's baby,
but he understands that.
I know that George will understand.
He knows already how badly
I want my own baby,
but I'm a little worried
of what he might think in the future.
Darling, you're being a little bit silly.
You know that George loves you now,
if only from the fact that
he's willing to let you have a baby
through this artificial insemination.
Then you think we should
go through with this?
I certainly do.
It's obvious that you
not only want a baby,
you need one.
You're getting neurotic, darling,
from worrying about this business.
That's a relief to know that you think
we should have a baby as the doctor suggested.
I was worried about several things--
George, myself,
what all our friends would think.
Why should they know?
None of them knows of George's
inability to be a father,
do they?
No, of course not.
Then you don't think we should let them know
that George isn't the father of our baby
when we have it?
I don't think it's any of their business.
There's no reason for anyone to know
that it isn't George's child
as well as your own.
That's what I think too.
Of course, Cathy.
Now, I'd better be leaving.
If I were you, I'd call George right away,
and tell him that you wanna
go through with this thing.
And then I'd call Dr. Wright.
That's exactly what I'll do, Mother.
Thanks for your advice, darling,
you've helped us so much.
Silly! You know I'd do anything I could
to help you two.
Now if you want me to come down
to Dr. Wright's office with you,
just give me a call.
I'd better run now.
- Bye, Cathy.
- Goodbye, Mother--I mean, Grandmother.
Yes, Mr. Peterson.
Well, I'm sure you'll find
that you'll be all right in the morning.
Mm-hmm, I understand.
Well, if you're not better
in the morning, give me a call.
Very well.
All right, goodbye.
I'm very happy to see
that you've reached your decision.
I'm sure that you will find
it was a sensible one.
We're sure of it, Dr. Wright.
It will be necessary for you
to sign this paper,
which is your permission
and waiver of responsibility
for this insemination.
Right here, please.
And this side, Mr. Bennett.
Will you come in, please, Miss Mason?
Thank you.
This will take about half an hour.
- Can you wait outside, Mr. Bennett, please?
- Sure.
Miss Mason, will you prepare
Mrs. Bennett for an insemination?
Right this way, Mrs. Bennett.
Is she all right, is--
is everything all right?
Well, young man,
yes to the first question.
As to the second,
well, you must realize that there's
a certain element of chance involved,
just as in a normal conception.
If this one doesn't work,
we'll just have to try again.
When will you want to see me
again, Doctor?
In about two weeks, I think, Mrs. Bennett.
Will you make the appointment,
please, Miss Mason?
Yes, Doctor. Will two weeks from today
at the same time be satisfactory?
Will I need any other treatments, Doctor?
No, my dear,
not if this one is successful.
You'll be no different than any
normal woman bearing her child,
and I see no reason for you to tell
your friends that George is not the father.
In fact, from my past experience in these
cases, I strongly advise against it.
I guess you should know best, Dr. Wright.
Well, Mr. Bennett, you two aren't
the only ones I've had with this problem.
Do you realize there are an estimated
five to ten percent of married couples
with this same difficulty?
And I thought we were an original family.
Now, George, relax.
Cathy'll be all right.
You're not the first man
whose wife had a baby.
Well, it's the first time
it ever happened to me.
I mean, to Cathy.
But why does it have to take so long,
why don't they let me stay with her?
But, George, Cathy is okay.
Dr. Wright told you not to worry.
But where is Dr. Wright,
where did he go?
Why isn't he with her?
He'll be here soon enough.
My goodness, women have been having babies
ever sense the beginning of time,
and most without doctors or hospitals.
Here's Dr. Wright now.
Dr. Wright, how is Cathy,
is she all right?
How long's it going to be?
Cathy's going to be fine, George.
You better get hold of yourself.
Why don't you sit down,
smoke a cigarette?
I smoked a whole pack of those things
since I've been here, Doctor,
I'm worried about Cathy.
Yes, I know.
Say, uh, why don't you run out
and buy a pack of cigarettes?
I haven't got any either.
If you're sure nothing
will happen while I'm gone.
I'll get you a pack, too, Doctor.
Go ahead, George.
I'm sure Catherine isn't even
in the delivery room yet,
or Dr. Wright wouldn't be here.
There goes a typical expectant father.
You'd think that when
a man's wife was having a baby,
the end of the world was at hand.
You told me that you wanted
to talk with me, Doctor.
Is it something about Cathy?
Well, to tell you the truth,
I just wanted to get that young man
something to do
before he decided to tear
the hospital apart.
Then Catherine is all right?
She's in no danger?
My dear, a woman during childbirth
is always in danger.
This might be a difficult birth.
Mothers nowadays are not like
our mothers were.
Dr. Wright,
come to the delivery room, please.
- Dr. Wright, come to the delivery room, please.
- Well, that's it.
When George gets back, you'd better
tell him to change that order to cigars.
Oh, bless our newborn infant.
Our baby, God adore,
Till love shall gently lead us
home to the eternal shore.
He doesn't want a doll, he's a boy.
Well, Daddy, are you happy
with your little family?
Yes, honey.
This is everything I've worked for.
Is my family happy with me?
Of course, silly,
you've been a wonderful father.
It's been a wonderful five years.
Look, Mama, look, Mama.
- What is it, dear?
- I drawed a picture of my baby brother
with a birthday cake.